amelinenussbaumer.github.io



ameline.nussbaumer@gmail.com

×

3 Sanctuary Drive #2 14850 Ithaca NY USA



+1 607 279 8567

AMELINE NUSSBAUMER

Instructional Design and Digital Learning Consultant

PROFILE

Dynamic and flexible professional with 7 years experience managing online and blended adult learning projects in international organisations. Strong experience in the design and production of interactive learning resources, well-versed in graphic design and communications. Experienced in project management and comfortable in multi-cultural contexts.

EDUCATION

MSc in Comparative and International Education University of Oxford | UK 2013 - 2014

BA (Hons) in Education and Modern Languages

University of Cambridge | UK 2008 - 2012

IT SKILLS

- Authoring Tools (Captivate, Storyline, Elucidat, BranchTrack, Vyond)
- LMS (CrossKnowledge, Moodle)
- Graphic design (Adobe Suite)
- Information Management (Office, Slack, Trello, Jive)
- Communications (Hootsuite)
- Web programming (HTML, CSS)

LANGUAGES

- French (mothertongue)
- English (bilingual)
- German (working proficiency)
- Spanish (basic)

REFERENCE

Lila Schneider-Beuchat

Learning Design Manager, ICRC lischneider@icrc.org

+41 22 730 33 38

EXPERIENCE

Instructional Design and Digital Learning Consultant

Oct 2020 - Current

I design, produce and deliver learning paths to meet customer needs and objectives. This includes instructional design, graphic production, and creation of the training on the LMS platform.

- Designed training paths for large audiences (including all-staff compliance training), managing strict project deadlines
- Produced branching scenarios and rapid learning modules to create engaging and practice-oriented content for learners

A Rocha Kenya (Conservation NGO) | Watamu, KE

Jan 2020 - August 2020

Field experience during which I was responsible for fundraising, communication, and local capacity-building initiatives.

- Led international grant applications and crowdfunding campaigns
- Managed external communication: website, annual report, newsletter, social media channels

International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) | Geneva, CH

July 2016 - Dec 2019

As Techno-Pedagogical Engineer, I managed learning initiatives liaising with internal experts and external providers. As Applications Trainer, I produced online learning courses, conducted trainings of trainers to build internal training capacity, and supported the digital transformation of the division.

- Managed the design and development of trainings in various formats: eLearning, blended, mobile app, face-to-face
- Produced user-friendly learning resources to facilitate colleagues' adoption and use of new digital tools
- Delivered training of trainers and regular internal workshops on training practices and digital tools
- Designed and facilitated online communities of practice and online learning paths

United Nations Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR) | Geneva, CH

Sept 2014 - June 2016

As eLearning officer, I gained broad experience in the development, promotion and evaluation of online training courses, as well as key skills in project management and communication.

- Facilitated, translated, and evaluated eLearning courses on Moodle
- Co-organized an international Forum (logistics and content)